Speaker: You are juggling some five balls in the air: work, family, health, friends, and spirit.
Work is a rubber ball. If you drop it, it will bounce back.
But the other four balls are made of glass. If you drop one of these, they will never be the same.
You must understand that and strive for balance in your life.
It can sometimes seem as if life is just one long list of things to do.
There are the demands of a stressful job, dealing with constant meetings,
deadlines, emails, and phone calls.
And then there’s the housework, shopping, childcare,
and cooking to fit in before we can even think about finding time to see friends,
chat with the family, and chill out.
No wonder so many people find it difficult to get their work–life balance right.
But creating that balance and making the space in our busy lives is central to our happiness and well-being.
There’s plenty of research to show that many of us struggle to achieve
the right balance between work and the rest of our life,
between the things we must or should do and the things we’d like to do.
As a result, we frequently feel overstressed and under-rested.
In the UK, a typical employee works for around 38 hours per week and takes 28 days’ holiday a year.
Sixty per cent of employees say they work longer hours than they would like,
with 20% saying they often or always feel exhausted in their work.
Office workers, for example, say they are frequently expected to work in their spare time,
replying to emails or taking out-of-hours calls.
In fact, research suggests people work an extra eight unpaid hours each week this way.
And for many, this work culture is unsustainable.
Two thirds of UK workers say they have suffered a work-related health issue in the last year,
with two of the most common being anxiety and disrupted sleep patterns.
More than a quarter said their job had a negative impact on their personal life.
And this is a problem for employers, too.
In the UK, employee burnout costs British businesses around £45 billion per year.